Read family papers LCP.Read
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series VI. General John Meredith Read Jr.
  - Subseries VIII. Photographs
    - Prints, information on Read memorial, sketches, 1796, 1790, 1800, undated (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - General John Meredith Read Jr. photograph album, circa 1805 (Volume 145)
    - General John Meredith Read Jr. photograph album, circa 1876-1877 (Volume 146)
    - Hand painted folder by Queen Olga of Greece, 1878 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, 1878, undated (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of people and places (mostly English) used for genealogical research, circa 1888 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Photographs for research and writing, France (labeled), 1893, undated (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Photographs for research and writing, France (labeled), 1893, 1898, undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Photographs for research and writing, France (labeled), 1893, 1898, undated (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Bruckman's portrait collection prints, undated (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Photograph album of Beedon, Barton Court, Abingdon, Appleford, Culham, Wallingford, Leamington, Oxford, Brocket Hall, Hatfield, Wheathampstead, Ayot., undated (Volume 147)
    - Photographs and prints used for research and writing, undated (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Photographs for genealogical research (England), undated (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Photographs for research and writing, France (labeled), undated (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of artwork, interiors and exteriors of buildings (labeled), undated (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of individuals (mostly labeled), undated (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Photographs of [opera singers?], undated (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Portrait photographs used for genealogical research, undated (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Prints and photographs for research and writing, France (mostly labeled), undated (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Prints and sketches, undated (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Prints of portraits, undated (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Prints of portraits, mostly family members, undated (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Prints, sketches, tombstone engraving, undated (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Subseries IX. Subject Files
    - "The Oxford Chronological Tables of History, 1838 (Volume 148)
    - Journal, circa 1857 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Clubs and societies scrapbook, 1860-1888 (Volume 149)
    - Scrapbook: "Alabama Claims" and "Anglo-American Relations during the Civil War", 1865-1869 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook (formerly titled "Clippings"), 1877-1878 (Volume 150)
    - General John Meredith Read Jr. autobiographical notes, circa 1879 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - General John Meredith Read Jr. autobiographical notes, circa 1879 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Freemasons scrapbook (possibly compiled by Harmon Pumpelly Read), 1880-1910 (Volume 151)
    - "Historical Manuscripts on Greece", circa 1880 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook/letterbook (formerly "Letters"), 1885 (Volume 152)
    - Correspondence and writings with M. A. de Quatrefages, 1889 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - "Dinners given by General and Mrs. Meredith Read," guest lists, table settings, menus, 1889-1896 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Interview with General John Meredith Read Jr. on the American presidential elections, newspaper clippings, 1896 November (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Pencil sketch, watercolor, two photographs, undated (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - "Horace et Son Temps," manuscripts and notes by unknown author, undated (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Journal, undated (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Engravings (depicting a variety of images including literature and medieval times), undated (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Les Bibliophiles Contemporains scrapbook, 1890-1895 (Box 73, Folder 2-16)
  - Subseries X. Writings and Research by General John Meredith Read II
    - Speech pamphlets, 1865-1868 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Drafts and notes for "Life and Lineage of His royal Highness Prince Albert", 1865-1868 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - "A Historical Inquiry Concerning Henry Hudson," related advertisement pamphlets, shipment forms, and correspondence, 1865-1868 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Writings and personal papers, 1876-1896 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Notebook: "Notes Upon Cannes Oxybian Days", circa 1879 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Notebook: "Oxybian Days and Grecian Memories in Provence by General Meredith Read", 1879 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Copies of correspondence from Richard Eliot, 1879-1896 (Volume 153)
    - Copies of correspondence from Richard Eliot, 1879-1896 (Volume 154)
    - Copies of letters from Edward Gibbon, Lord Chesterfield, and Mr. Stanhope, 1879-1896 (Volume 155)
    - Copies of letters from Mr. W. Harte, inclusive, 1879-1895 (Volume 156)
    - Correspondence and addressees a Rosset de Rochefort (1765-1770), 1879-1896 (Volume 157)
    - Titres de la Grotte Liasse de la Famille Teirssoniere, 1879-1896 (Volume 158)
    - Evian: Famille de Blonay Etat des Biens (1818-1846), 1879-1896 (Volume 159)
    - Titres de Possession de la Grotte, 1879-1896 (Volume 160)
    - Titres de la Grotte: Liasse de Monsieur George de Montagny, 1879-1896 (Volume 161)
    - Memoir sur les Personnes et Sur les Familles a qui on Donne en France le Titre de Prince, 1879-1896 (Volume 162)
    - Collection de documents de Monsieur Ernest Charannes, 1879-1896 (Volume 163)
    - Collection de fue Monsieur A. Veideil, 1879-1896 (Volume 164)
    - Collection de Mde Constantine Grenier, 1879-1896 (Volume 165)
    - Correspondence and Notes Relating to the Town and Canton of Berne, 1879-1896 (Volume 166)
    - Collection of Madame Constantin Grenier, 1879-1896 (Volume 167)
    - Autobiographical notes, circa 1879 (Volume 168)
    - Personal writings and correspondence, 1879-1896 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings: various articles by General John Meredith Read II and collected works, 1881, 1883, 1886 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Notes on Henry Hudson, 1887 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - "Tribute to Arsene Houssaye," by Meredith Read printed in the Home Journal, 1896 April 15 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Proofs of silhouette illustrations for "historical studies", circa 1896 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Eighteenth and seventeenth century material, undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Vers de la main de Monsieur de malesherbes and copies of other letters, 1710-1730 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - L. M. du Loisngne to the Marquis de St. Michel, 1712 January 20, 1712 April 15 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Madame Necker aux Editeurs de Oeuvres de Voltaire; Madame Necker a Monsieur Jacques Godard, circa 1730 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - F. Random to the Marquise and Marquis de Saint Michel, 1730 December 1-6 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Lettre de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur le Marquis d'Argens, 1736 October 18 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a Monsieur Thiriot, 1741 April 6 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Copies of correspondence from Edward Eliot, 1746-1747 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Lettre de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur Lambert, 1754 January (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Lettre de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur Lambert [?], 1756 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Lettre de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur de Labat, Baron de Grandcourt, 1756 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Lettre de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur Boris Soltikoff, 1759 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Lettre de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur le Due de Choiseul, 1757 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1763 April-December (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1764 April-December (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1765 April-December (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1766 April-December (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Letter from Bonnet to Lesage, 1763 November 15 (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1764 January 10 (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1764 January 22 (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1764 January 25 (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1764 February 13 (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1764 February 16 (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1764 February 8, 1764 February 22 (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1764 March 1, 1764 March 4 (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1764 May 28, 1764 June 9 (Box 76, Folder 26)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1764 June 19 (Box 76, Folder 27)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1765 April 13 (Box 76, Folder 28)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1765 September 3 (Box 76, Folder 29)
    - Fragment d'une lettre de Monsieur de Voltaire, 1765 (Box 76, Folder 30)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1766 February 10 (Box 76, Folder 31)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1766 July 12 (Box 76, Folder 32)
    - Letter from Edward Gibbon to Victor de Saussure, 1766 September 23 (Box 76, Folder 33)
    - Letter from Edward Gibbon to Victor de Saussure, 1766 September 23 (Box 76, Folder 34)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1767 January 23, 1767 February 25 (Box 76, Folder 35)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1767 February 28, 1767 June 7 (Box 76, Folder 36)
    - Lettres de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur Marin, 1767, 1772 (Box 76, Folder 37)
    - Lettre de Monsieur de Voltaire a Madame de La Beaumelle, 1767 June 25 (Box 76, Folder 38)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a Maillet du Boullay Ferney, 1768 (Box 76, Folder 39)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1768 January 27, 1768 February 25 (Box 76, Folder 40)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1768 February 27, 1768 May 6 (Box 76, Folder 41)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1768 April 14 (Box 76, Folder 42)
    - Lettre de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur Lekain [?], 1769 (Box 76, Folder 43)
    - Lettres de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur Cabaeau, 1769, 1771 (Box 76, Folder 44)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1769 August 10 (Box 76, Folder 45)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1770 June 25, 1770 June 28 (Box 76, Folder 46)
    - Lettre de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur le-Cardinal de Bernis Datee de Ferney, 1771 November 25 (Box 76, Folder 47)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1771 December 6 (Box 76, Folder 48)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1772 November 19 (Box 76, Folder 49)
    - Lettre de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1775 August 22 (Box 76, Folder 50)
    - Lettres de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur Marin, 1773 March 1, 1773 August 9 (Box 76, Folder 51)
    - Lettres de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur Marin, 1774 March 21, 1775 October 14 (Box 76, Folder 52)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1775 September 19, 1775 September 26 (Box 76, Folder 53)
    - Lettres de Voltaire a de Vegobre, 1776 February 28, 1776 April 15 (Box 76, Folder 54)
    - Letter from W. Windham Esquire to Monsieur le Duc de Noailles, 1792 April 27 (Box 76, Folder 55)
    - Letter from William Hayley Esquire to Mr. Nicol, 1793 October 11 (Box 76, Folder 56)
    - Lettre de Frederic II, Roi de Prusse, 1779 February 27 (Box 76, Folder 57)
    - Billet de Monsieur de Voltaire a Monsieur de Malesherbes, undated (Box 76, Folder 58)
- Series VII. Harmon Pumpelly Read
  - Correspondence, business and personal, 1880-1906 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1880s (Volume 169)
  - Contents of blotting paper notebook, correspondence from Henry Hobart Bellas, John Meredith Read II, Smith E. Lane, Delaware Society of the Cincinnati, and others, 1892-1908 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Playbills, paperwork for the transfer of stock in the Library Company of Philadelphia, death notice for John Meredith Read II, book plates, and correspondence, 1884-1911 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1885 (Volume 170)
  - Correspondence from Henry Hobart Bellas, National guard of Southern New York headquarters of tenth battalion, and others; bookplates, 1886-1901 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence regarding Madam C. M. Carron's health, 1888-1891 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook (formerly listed under General John M. Read), 1889-1897 (Volume 171)
  - Correspondence, bills, and receipts regarding C. M. Carron's stay at the Insane Retreat (mostly Louise de Carron, H. P. Stearns, and Harmon Read); one unidentified photograph, 1890-1891 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, personal, 1890-1906 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Financial papers, bills, receipts, and accounts, 1890-1906 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Madam C. M. Carron from Insane Retreat, 1891 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook of the death of General John Meredith Read, 1896-1899 (Volume 172)
  - Correspondence, business and personal, 1897-1914 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, telegrams, receipts, playbills, newspaper clippings, Cadwalader and Meredith family tree by John Meredith Read, 1897-1907 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - "With Pen and Camera at Niagara Falls", 1898 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Writings, circa 1900 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Ephemera, circa 1900 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Funeral notices for Delphine Marie Pumpelly Read, 1902 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Contents of scrapbook with unknown sketches; blank postcards, advertisements, newspaper clippings, 1908 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook cover (contents in box 79, folder 5), circa 1908 (Volume 173)
  - Blotting paper notebook, undated (Box 79, Folder 6)
- Series VIII. John Meredith Read III: Autobiography and family history, circa 1900 (Volume 174)
- Series IX. James Read account book for Rings End and Point (part 9), 1761-1765 (Volume 175)
- Series X. Collected Meredith family papers
  - Correspondence from John Salisbury, Watkins Williams Wynn, Campbell-Johnson, undated, 1667 January 29, 1898 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, [1777-1778?] (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1777 January 9 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1777 January 14 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1777 January 16 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Certificate of damages, 1778 July 8, 1778 August 19 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Samuel Meredith commission, 1786 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from wife, Peggy Meredith, to Samuel Meredith, 1786 December (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1788 August 18 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1788 August 22 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1789 March 26 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1790 February 7 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1790 March 22 (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1790 April 6 (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1790 April 15 (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1790 July 1 (Box 80, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1790 July 7 (Box 80, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Meredith to wife, Peggy Meredith, 1790 July 14 (Box 80, Folder 17)
  - Samuel Meredith bank book, 1793-1800 (Box 80, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence from E. Meredith to Samuel Meredith, 1799 July 13 (Box 80, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence from [Peggy Meredith?] to Samuel Meredith, 1799 November 20 (Box 80, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence to Betsy Meredith from [M. M.?], 1799 November 26 (Box 80, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence from M. Read to Samuel Meredith and Betsy Meredith, 1801 August 23 (Box 80, Folder 22)
  - Copy of correspondence from Thomas Jefferson to Samuel Meredith, 1801 September 4 (Box 80, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence from L. Cadwalader to Peggy Meredith, 1801 September 17 (Box 80, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence from Martha Read to Peggy Meredith, 1815 August 22 (Box 80, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence from Martha Read to Peggy Meredith, 1817 January 27 (Box 80, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence from James Gibson to Peggy Meredith, 1817 February 24 (Box 80, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Dickinson to Peggy Meredith, 1817 April 22 (Box 80, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence from [M.M.?] to mother, 1819 September 9 (Box 80, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence to Margaret Meredith from Mary, 1820 March 7 (Box 80, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence from John Read to Thomas Meredith, 1820 October 7 (Box 80, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence from Lloyd P. Smith to John Meredith Read, 1863 January 3 (Box 80, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence from P. Dickinson to John Meredith Read, 1864 September 20 (Box 80, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence from [M. B.?] to Thomas Meredith Maxwell regarding Meredith Monument Association, 1877 September 27 (Box 80, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence from Thomas Meredith Maxwell to General John Meredith Read Jr., 1888 October 24 (Box 80, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence from Thomas Meredith Maxwell to General John Meredith Read Jr., 1888 October 25 (Box 80, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence from Thomas Meredith Maxwell to General John Meredith Read Jr., 1888 November 6 (Box 80, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence from Thomas Meredith Maxwell to General John Meredith Read Jr., 1889 February 11 (Box 80, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence from Thomas Meredith Maxwell to General John Meredith Read Jr., 1889 October 23 (Box 80, Folder 39)
  - General John Meredith Read Jr.'s Meredith family Genealogy, 1892 (Box 80, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence from Mary Dickinson to Harmon Read, 1892 February 29 (Box 80, Folder 41)
  - [Information regarding the acquisition of the Meredith family papers], undated (Box 80, Folder 42)